<resources>
    <string name="app_name">HumanNeeds</string>
    <string name="main_welcome">Welcome to HumanNeeds!</string>
    <string name="main_description">By this app, you have a unique opportunity to get a
        picture about your needs.\nBased on these, you receive some characteristics about yourself.</string>

    <!--string name="info1">By using the app, you accept the</string>
    <string name="info2">Terms of Use</string>
    <string name="info3">and the</string>
    <string name="info4">Privacy Policy</string-->

    <string name="main_edit_text_hint">Please, type your name!</string>
    <string name="main_name_empty">Please, type your name to continue!</string>
    <string name="main_btn_text">Start</string>
    <string name="problem">Problem occurred.</string>

    <string name="statements_header_part">\'s human needs</string>
    <string name="statements_show_result_btn">Click to view the results!</string>

    <string name="question">How do you feel about the following statements?</string>
    <string name="fragment_answer1">Absolutely agree</string>
    <string name="fragment_answer2">Agree</string>
    <string name="fragment_answer3">Partly agree/disagree</string>
    <string name="fragment_answer4">Disagree</string>
    <string name="fragment_answer5">Absolutely disagree</string>

    <string name="of">\u0020of\u0020</string>

    <string name="results">\'s results</string>
    <string name="share">Share</string>

    <string name="share_welcome">These statistics are about %s\'s human needs!\n\n</string>
    <string name="share_brief_title">There are three needs to highlight:\n</string>
    <string name="share_brief">
        The most important need is %s.\n
    The secondary important need is %s.\n
    The least important need is %s.\n\n</string>
    <string name="share_details">Here are the detailed statistics:\n</string>
    <string name="share_detail_item">
        Need name: %s\n
        Score: %s\n
        Number of given \"Absolutely agree\" answer: %s\n
        Number of given \"Agree\" answer: %s\n
        Number of given \"Partly agree/disagree\" answer: %s\n
        Number of given \"Disagree\" answer: %s\n
        Number of given \"Absolutely disagree\" answer: %s\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="share_from">\nShared from HumanNeeds app</string>
    <string name="share_title">Sharing your statistics&#8230;</string>
    <string name="share_subject">Statistics from HumanNeeds app</string>

    <string name="least_imp_alert">
        Please, read through the description of this need to get to know it better. While reading,
        try to focus on if this need is really not so important for you.
    </string>

    <!--string name="privacy_policy">https://sites.google.com/view/humanneeds-en-privacy-policy</string>
    <string name="terms_of_use">https://sites.google.com/view/humanneeds-en-terms</string-->
    <string name="agree_terms_privacy">By continuing, you agree
        to the &lt;a href=https://sites.google.com/view/humanneeds-en-terms>Terms of Use&lt;/a> and
        the &lt;a href=https://sites.google.com/view/humanneeds-en-privacy-policy>Privacy Policy&lt;/a>.</string>

    <string name="statements_missing">It seems you have gone through the statements
        but meanwhile, you missed one or more:\u0020</string>

    <string name="result_first_need">1st need</string>
    <string name="result_second_need">2nd need</string>
    <string name="result_first_and_second_need">1st &amp; 2nd needs</string>
    <string name="result_last_need">Least important need</string>

    <string name="need_certainty">Certainty</string>
    <string name="need_uncertainty_variety">Uncertainty/Variety</string>
    <string name="need_significance">Significance</string>
    <string name="need_love_connection">Love/Connection</string>
    <string name="need_growth">Growth</string>
    <string name="need_contribution">Contribution</string>

    <string name="about_label">About app</string>
    <string name="about_logo_content_description">Logo Image</string>
    <string name="about_mission_label">Mission</string>
    <string name="about_mission1">
        HumanNeeds creates input based statistics about your possible behavior/characteristics.\nThis
        app calculates the scores of each need types, and then gives you
        information about the most relevant ones.
    </string>
    <string name="about_mission2">
        The different human needs are the followings:\n
        Certainty\n
        Uncertainty/Variety\n
        Significance\n
        Love/Connection\n
        Growth\n
        Contribution
    </string>
    <string name="about_mapping_label">Score mapping</string>
    <string name="about_mapping1">
        For each of the available options, there are different points which
        are summarized to have the final score of each of the need types.
    </string>
    <string name="about_mapping2">
        \"Absolutely agree\" represents the point of 1.0.\n
        \"Agree\" represents the point of 0.75.\n
        \"Partly agree/disagree\" represents the point of 0.5.\n
        \"Disagree\" represents the point of 0.25.\n
        \"Absolutely disagree\" represents the point of 0.0.
    </string>
    <string name="about_icons_label">Icons</string>
    <string name="about_icons">The used icons are from the
        &lt;a href=https://material.io/tools/icons/?style=baseline>Material Design&lt;/a> web page.</string>
    <string name="about_documents_label">Documents</string>
    <string name="about_documents1">
        By using the app, you hereby accept the
        &lt;a href=https://sites.google.com/view/humanneeds-en-terms>Terms of Use&lt;/a> and
        the &lt;a href=https://sites.google.com/view/humanneeds-en-privacy-policy>Privacy Policy&lt;/a>.
    </string>
    <string name="about_documents2">This is a free software licensed under
        &lt;a href=https://www.gnu.org/licenses/agpl-3.0.en.html>GNU AGPL v3&lt;/a>.
    </string>
    <string name="about_information_label">Information source</string>
    <string name="about_information">
        The information about the human needs and their descriptions are from
        &lt;a href=http://www.lifecoachinginterventions.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/Significance-of-Your-Most-Important-Needs.pdf>
        LifeCoachingInterventions.com&lt;/a>.</string>

    <!--string name="icons_url">https://material.io/tools/icons/?style=baseline</string-->

    <string-array name="certainty_headers">
        <item>Your beliefs</item>
        <item>How this belief serves you</item>
        <item>The principles you lose sight of</item>
        <item>The consequences of losing sight of this principle</item>
        <item>Focus</item>
        <item>Energy</item>
        <item>Health</item>
        <item>What you avoid</item>
        <item>Strengths</item>
        <item>Communication style</item>
        <item>Stress</item>
        <item>Defensiveness</item>
        <item>Emotions</item>
        <item>Your goal for achieving growth and balance</item>
        <item>What to do</item>
        <item>What interferes with your goal</item>
        <item>How others can support you in your goal</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="certainty_values">
        <item>I need to feel secure, safe and comfortable and I need to make sure that I
will be secure, safe and comfortable in the future. Avoiding pain is very
important to me. I can\'t be happy when I\'m uncertain about things.</item>
        <item>I avoid risks and I carefully plan for the future. I\'m careful and I take care
of myself. People know I am predictable. I know how to be organized.</item>
        <item>The future is unpredictable; all we have is the present moment. Where
there is no risk, there is no gain. It is possible to be uncertain about the
future, yet happy in the present.</item>
        <item>I limit my new experiences. I have trouble letting love flow when I don\'t
feel secure and comfortable. I have trouble involving myself with people for
fear that they will cause me pain. People sometimes think that I\'m
controlling. I may seem unenthusiastic and even boring. I am predictable
at the cost of being spontaneous.</item>
        <item>I focus on stability, on habitual routines and on preparing and saving for
the future. I prefer work that is stable and easy instead of work that is
challenging and stretches my abilities.</item>
        <item>I put my energy into organizing a secure and comfortable environment. I\'m
focused inwardly on evaluating my level of comfort-discomfort.</item>
        <item>I like to take care of myself, but my need for comfort may lead me to over
eating or drinking.</item>
        <item>I tend to avoid new people and new experiences. I avoid relationships
where there is not full commitment. I avoid threats and hazards. I fear not
being in control.</item>
        <item>I am organized, reliable and dependable. I can create a home and work
environment that is pleasing and where people can feel comfortable.</item>
        <item>I often talk about my internal states, emphasizing whether I feel grounded,
protected and safe. Words that I frequently use are: comfort, security,
stability, and predictability.</item>
        <item>I am stressed when something new is required of me, when I don\'t know
what\'s going to happen next. Changes in plans, even if there are new
opportunities, stress me out. I put pressure on myself to make sure I don\'t
feel insecure.</item>
        <item>I get defensive when I\'m required to change my habits or to deal with new
people and new situations. I can get angry when people challenge my need
to feel comfortable and to have predictability in my life.</item>
        <item>I worry a great deal about the future. I\'m very sensitive to danger and
experience fear easily. I sometimes envy people who have more money or a
larger income than I do.</item>
        <item>My goal is to be able to live in the present, to experience the moment
without focusing on what will happen next and what the future might hold.
I need to take some risks in order to reap some benefits. I need to accept
that uncertainty and insecurity are a part of life.</item>
        <item>I need to stretch myself by learning new things and having new
experiences. Instead of fear and anxiety, I need to learn to experience
excitement and joy. I need to learn to enjoy a challenge. I need to develop
courage and to be able to act even when I feel insecure. I need to get a
reality check from others about my fears and concerns.</item>
        <item>My wish to feel comfortable and to plan for the future interferes with my
goal. I am over protective and controlling. I require too much certainty. I
can be pessimistic about the future.</item>
        <item>Others can support me by introducing me to new experiences and by
encouraging more spontaneity and fun. They can counter my doubts and
fears in realistic ways.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="uncertainty_headers">
        <item>Your beliefs</item>
        <item>How this belief serves you</item>
        <item>The principles you lose sight of</item>
        <item>The consequences of losing sight of this principle</item>
        <item>Focus</item>
        <item>Energy</item>
        <item>Health</item>
        <item>What you avoid</item>
        <item>Strengths</item>
        <item>Communication style</item>
        <item>Stress</item>
        <item>Defensiveness</item>
        <item>Emotions</item>
        <item>Your goal for achieving growth and balance</item>
        <item>What to do</item>
        <item>What interferes with your goal</item>
        <item>How others can support you in your goal</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="uncertainty_values">
        <item>I believe that happiness comes from having many different experiences and
challenges that exercise my emotional, intellectual or physical range. My
emotional well-being requires uncertainty, suspense and surprise. I need
the excitement that comes from variety.</item>
        <item>I have many interests. People usually see me as entertaining, dynamic,
interesting and fun to be with. I can always find new things to do and new
adventures. I have many friends from different backgrounds. I interact well
with people of all ages and all walks of life. I am trusting and think the best
of people. I\'m not easily bored because I can always find something
interesting to do. I\'m fun loving and carefree. I\'m usually upbeat and I like
to enjoy life to the fullest.</item>
        <item>To have balance in life there are times where the priority is stability and
responsibility in relationships. Sometimes it\'s necessary to focus on
subjects and tasks that are not particularly interesting in order to obtain
rewards later on. You can\'t always trust everyone.</item>
        <item>People sometimes feel they can\'t count on me, that I am uncommitted,
unreliable and don\'t take care of my loved ones. I can be involved in too
many things at once and neglect what I need to do to make sure that I\'m
safe and comfortable. I can get myself into dangerous or difficult situations
physically, emotionally and financially. Sometimes I can be careless about
things that I know are important to me and to others. My trusting,
optimistic nature makes it possible for people to take advantage of me.
Studying, memorizing and sitting still can be difficult for me and may
result in challenges in my career. I can become unfocused.</item>
        <item>I focus on seeking excitement and change. My focus is on what is new and
interesting or challenging. While involved in an adventure, I\'m planning
the next one. I like suspense and exertion.</item>
        <item>I\'m energetic and need to focus my energy on several projects. I\'m focused
outwardly on what there is to do next. Whether I am spectator or an active
participant, I constantly seek stimulation and entertainment.</item>
        <item>I stay fit in order to be involved in all the activities that interest me.</item>
        <item>I avoid a life of habits and routines. I don\'t like to be involved in
relationships that restrict me from new challenges and new experiences. I
avoid boredom.</item>
        <item>I\'m enthusiastic, independent and fun to be with. I like to live so that there
is never a dull moment. I see the glass half full. I\'m a leader and I can be
the life of the party. I\'m not afraid of taking risks. I\'m playful and
optimistic.</item>
        <item>I like to talk about different projects and adventures. I can be so
enthusiastic in my conversation that I forget to listen to the other person or
to ask their opinion. Sometimes I become restless and need to stand up
and walk around during a conversation. Words that I frequently use are:
fear, instability, change, chaos, entertainment, suspense, exertion,
surprise, conflict and crisis.</item>
        <item>I am stressed when I don\'t have the time or the means to become involved
in new challenges and adventures. A routine life stresses me. I\'m upset if
my physical condition prevents me from participating in activities I like.
Restrictions on my freedom are very stressful to me.</item>
        <item>I get defensive when someone attempts to impose routines or schedules or
to restrict my social life. I can get angry when people criticize my desire for
adventure and entertainment.</item>
        <item>I like to feel excited, thrilled, exuberant, joyful, and adventurous. I do
everything possible to avoid boredom. My ability to experience a broad
range of emotions makes it easy for me to feel empathy towards others. I
know I can experience what they are experiencing.</item>
        <item>My goal is to be able to have roots, stability and permanent relationships
while still enjoying times of excitement and adventure. Taking good care of
myself and of others has to be more of a priority for me. I need to be a
better judge of character. I need to live more in the present than in the
future.</item>
        <item>I need to focus more on the present and less on the next adventure in the
future. I need to create a stable, harmonious environment for myself and to
develop long lasting relationships. I need to focus on activities that are not
particularly exciting but that lead to important accomplishments in the
future.</item>
        <item>There are an infinite number of new, exciting experiences that are open to
me. It\'s difficult to choose among them and it\'s difficult to stay with what I
need to focus on in the present. Sometimes I focus too much on my self and
what I want. I can be easily distracted and diverted.</item>
        <item>Others can support me by encouraging me and praising me when I stick to
a task that is not particularly exciting and when I take steps towards taking
care of myself and providing stability for myself and my loved ones. People
can help me to stay in the present.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="significance_headers">
        <item>Your beliefs</item>
        <item>How this belief serves you</item>
        <item>The principles you lose sight of</item>
        <item>The consequences of losing sight of these principles</item>
        <item>Focus</item>
        <item>Energy</item>
        <item>Health</item>
        <item>What you avoid</item>
        <item>Strengths</item>
        <item>Communication style</item>
        <item>Stress</item>
        <item>Defensiveness</item>
        <item>Emotions</item>
        <item>Your goal for achieving growth and balance</item>
        <item>What to do</item>
        <item>What interferes with your goal</item>
        <item>How others can support you in your goal</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="significance_values">
        <item>I believe that happiness comes from feeling respected and important. I
need to be considered unique and special. I need for people to look up to
me and even fear me to a certain extent.</item>
        <item>I work hard at being different, special, and unique. I strive to be a leader. I
do whatever is necessary for people to look up to me, respect me and
admire me. I never want to be a follower.</item>
        <item>Sometimes love is more important than respect. It\'s difficult to love
someone who has to feel important all the time. Humility is an important
virtue. Being admired by many but loved by few may not be conducive to
happiness. “Heavy lies the head that bears the crown.” – Shakespeare –</item>
        <item>People sometimes dislike me because they see me as arrogant and full of
myself. I have to constantly work at being respected and admired. I have
trouble letting love flow when I don\'t feel important. People sometimes
think that I consider myself superior to everyone. I can come across as cold
and uncaring. I often find it difficult to have fun. I can be seen as closeminded.
I have trouble relating to others because I focus on differences
rather than commonalities. I\'m overly concerned with hierarchical pecking
orders.</item>
        <item>I focus on what to do to appear special, different and important. I will do
almost anything to preserve my uniqueness. I focus on playing the part of
someone very special. I need to feel proud of myself. I have high standards
and I live by them. I evaluate myself as compared to others. I need to be
heard, and sometimes “heard” to me, means being obeyed.</item>
        <item>I constantly ask myself whether people respect me and admire me. I\'m
watchful to correct any signs of lack of respect. I need to feel that I make a
difference in any situation. I\'m disciplined, competitive, and I can be a
perfectionist.</item>
        <item>If my sense of significance is tied to my appearance, endurance and
strength, I will do whatever it takes to stay fit and healthy. I may injure
myself by overdoing it while exercising or practicing a sport.</item>
        <item>I avoid people who don\'t admire me or treat me with respect. I avoid
situations where I can\'t feel that I\'m very important. I don\'t tolerate
rejection. I will do anything to avoid being over shadowed by others. I hate
losing face.</item>
        <item>I work hard and strive to deserve the respect and admiration I crave. I\'m
willing to take responsibility to the point of self-sacrifice. I\'m relentless in
accomplishing my goals. I\'m a leader. I stand up for what I believe in. I\'m
not afraid of risk or confrontation.</item>
        <item>I often talk about my accomplishments, my sacrifices, my intelligence, my
strengths and my attractiveness. I can be seen as overriding others\' view.
Some of the words that I frequently use are: pride, importance, standards,
achievement, performance, perfection, evaluation, discipline, competition
and rejection.</item>
        <item>I am stressed when I feel that I\'m not living up to my standards. Not being
respected and heard stresses me out, as well as feeling that I\'m not a
leader. I feel pressure to achieve prestige, power and status. I\'m stressed
from doing too much and from not being in touch with my values.</item>
        <item>I get defensive at the slightest criticism and when people tell me what to
do. Anything that implies that I\'m a follower, instead of a leader, puts me
on the defensive.</item>
        <item>I experience despair, anger and rage when I\'m not living up to my
standards and not accomplishing my goals. I can get angry when people
disagree with my values, beliefs and leadership. I can be impatient and
irritable.</item>
        <item>My goal is to be loved for who I am, not because of my accomplishments or
because of the respect and admiration of others. I need to learn to value
love and connection more than respect and admiration. I need to learn to
be humble and practice patience. I need to notice when my standards are
too high. I need to self-sacrifice less and love myself more.</item>
        <item>I need to get involved in experiences where I won\'t get any admiration or
special respect. I need to work less and love myself more. I need to indulge
in pleasurable experiences just for the sake of pleasure. I need to relax. I
need to pay attention to feelings and relationships.</item>
        <item>My constant need to feel special, important and a leader, interfere with my
goal. The high standards I hold myself to, and my willingness to sacrifice
interfere with my goal.</item>
        <item>Others can help me with my goal by introducing me to interesting,
challenging or fun experiences at which I\'m not an expert. They can
reassure me that they love me for who I am and not for my
accomplishments. They can remind me to slow down and encourage me to
work less and play more.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="love_headers">
        <item>Your beliefs</item>
        <item>How this belief serves you</item>
        <item>The principles you lose sight of</item>
        <item>The consequences of losing sight of this principle</item>
        <item>Focus</item>
        <item>Energy</item>
        <item>Health</item>
        <item>What you avoid</item>
        <item>Strengths</item>
        <item>Communication style</item>
        <item>Stress</item>
        <item>Defensiveness</item>
        <item>Emotions</item>
        <item>Your goal for achieving growth and balance</item>
        <item>What to do</item>
        <item>What interferes with your goal</item>
        <item>How others can support you in your goal</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="love_values">
        <item>In order to feel worthy I need to love and be loved. I need to have
meaningful connections with people. If I\'m not loved and I can\'t give my
love, I\'m worthless.</item>
        <item>I\'m kind a generous to those I love and I can be fiercely protective of them.
I\'m nurturing and responsible.</item>
        <item>You must love yourself first. You are not indispensable to others. To be
loved is not equal to being needed.</item>
        <item>In thinking of others first, I repress my own needs. I can become intrusive.
Often I\'m unable to say “no.” Because by giving to others I expect to be
loved, I\'m often disappointed. I\'m often not aware of my own needs. I can
be intrusive without realizing it.</item>
        <item>My focus is on the relationships with those I love and on how to satisfy
their needs. I have great empathy for the feelings and emotions of others. I
expect to be loved in return.</item>
        <item>My focus is on understanding others and meeting their needs. I like to feel
that I can help and I\'m proud of being able to do so. I need people\'s
approval and acceptance. I have high energy when it comes to giving. I
crave romantic love.</item>
        <item>I may be so focused on taking care of others that I neglect my own health.</item>
        <item>I will do almost anything to avoid feeling dispensable. I avoid
disappointing others and feeling unappreciated. It\'s hard for me to tolerate
rejection.</item>
        <item>I\'m generous, sensitive, supportive and helpful. I relate well to people of all
ages and all walks of life. I\'m a good companion and listener. I give good
advice. I give freely of my time, energy and material possessions. I
empathize with suffering. I have emotional depth.</item>
        <item>I am focused on others and I\'m friendly and open. I express myself well
and I\'m quick to give advice. I\'m supportive. Words that I frequently use
are: togetherness, passion, unity, warmth, tenderness, and desire.
Sometimes people experience me as emotionally intense.</item>
        <item>I am stressed when I\'m not appreciated for all I give and when I\'m not
loved in return. I\'m also stressed when sometimes people perceive me as
intrusive or controlling. Feeling needed by so many people is stressful and
my confusion about my own needs doesn\'t help. I invest too much in
challenging relationships. I sometimes envy what others have and what is
not emotionally available to me.</item>
        <item>I get defensive when people tell me how to live, especially when they insist
I should give less to others. I can get angry if I feel controlled and if people
attribute bad intentions to me. I can get enraged when people are cruel. I
can also become defensive when I feel misunderstood.</item>
        <item>I worry a great deal about others. I can easily attribute blame to myself
and/or to others. I sometimes experience resentment and I have angry
outbursts when I don\'t feel appreciated or I\'m treated inconsiderately.
When I\'m away from those I love, I feel great pain in missing them. I often
feel possessive about those I love. I feel deeply and I\'m idealistic. I long for
what is missing in my life. I can be very emotional and sink into
depression.</item>
        <item>I need to take care of myself better and to be more aware of my own needs.
I need to feel that I can be loved for who I am, not for what I give.</item>
        <item>I need to practice setting limits on what I give. I need to develop clarity
about my own needs and how to satisfy them. I need to be sensitive to
when I can be seen as intrusive or controlling. I need to honor my feelings
and my idealism.</item>
        <item>My need to help and to give to those I love interferes with my goal. I often
feel guilty when I pay attention to my own needs. My feelings of pride for
not paying attention to my needs interfere with my goal, as does my fear of
being selfish. I have difficulty in asking for anything and in receiving from
others. I believe that I am loved based on what I give.</item>
        <item>Others can model on my independence instead of becoming dependent on
what I give. Others could ask me about my needs and pay attention to
them. Give me appreciation for what I give and also appreciate whenever I
say “no.” People could focus on understanding me instead of trying to
change me.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="growth_headers">
        <item>Your beliefs</item>
        <item>How this belief serves you</item>
        <item>The principles you lose sight of</item>
        <item>The consequences of losing sight of this principle</item>
        <item>Focus</item>
        <item>Energy</item>
        <item>Health</item>
        <item>What you avoid</item>
        <item>Strengths</item>
        <item>Communication style</item>
        <item>Stress</item>
        <item>Defensiveness</item>
        <item>Emotions</item>
        <item>Your goal for achieving growth and balance</item>
        <item>What to do</item>
        <item>What interferes with your goal</item>
        <item>How others can support you in your goal</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="growth_values">
        <item>I need to constantly develop new skills, learn new things, and improve at
what I already know. I have to develop my self physically, emotionally,
intellectually and/or spiritually. I need to be constantly growing.</item>
        <item>There is always a new challenge and something new to learn. I\'m not
dependent on others in order to find joy in learning. I\'m self sufficient and
active in my pursuits. I\'m not attached to material possessions. It\'s not
about what I have; it\'s about what I know and what I\'m able to do.</item>
        <item>Connecting and giving to others can be more fulfilling than acquiring new
knowledge and skills. There can be more pleasure in sharing than in
accumulating.</item>
        <item>I can be seen as reserved and unwilling to share. I can become detached
and overly private. I tend to under value relationships.</item>
        <item>I focus on learning, studying, developing my skills and being the best I
could possibly be.</item>
        <item>I conserve my energy and focus away from feelings in order to learn
everything there is to be learned. I am self-contained and I set careful
limits to protect my time and privacy.</item>
        <item>If my need to grow is tied to developing physically, I will do whatever is
necessary to stay healthy and fit.</item>
        <item>I will do anything to avoid feeling inadequate or drained. I avoid demands
and intrusions on the privacy that allows me to focus on my own personal
growth.</item>
        <item>I\'m respectful of others. I\'m thoughtful, calm and dependable. I like to
think that I\'m a model of self - improvement for others.</item>
        <item>Because I like to focus on content and facts, people might see me as
distant. Words that I use frequently are: I, me, my self, know, learn, grow,
develop, understand, analyze, accomplish, goals.</item>
        <item>I\'m stressed when I feel tired or dependent on others. Intrusions on my
privacy are stressful to me.</item>
        <item>I become defensive when there are intrusions or limitations on what I want
to do. I can become angry when people interfere with my need for privacy.</item>
        <item>I\'m careful when expressing emotions but I can have outbursts of temper
when I feel intruded upon.</item>
        <item>My goal is to be able to pursue my growth while enjoying relationships and
connection with people. I need to be able to experience joy and pleasure in
many ways, not just by learning.</item>
        <item>I need to find balance in life by focusing more on others, rather than on my
own growth and development. I need to experience pleasure in giving, to
be less reserved and give priority to love and relationships. I need to take
better care of those I love.</item>
        <item>The belief that I\'m not worthy if I don\'t constantly improve myself. The
importance that I give to privacy interferes with my goal. I need to
recognize that I can appear self-centered.</item>
        <item>Others can appreciate my ability to be self sufficient and independent as
well as my willingness to live and let live, while at the same time
encouraging me to be more social and loving.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="contribution_headers">
        <item>Your beliefs</item>
        <item>How this belief serves you</item>
        <item>The principles you lose sight of</item>
        <item>The consequences of losing sight of these principles</item>
        <item>Focus</item>
        <item>Energy</item>
        <item>Health</item>
        <item>What you avoid</item>
        <item>Strengths</item>
        <item>Communication style</item>
        <item>Stress</item>
        <item>Defensiveness</item>
        <item>Emotions</item>
        <item>Your goal for achieving growth and balance</item>
        <item>What I need to do</item>
        <item>What interferes with your goal</item>
        <item>How others can support you in your goal</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="contribution_values">
        <item>Life is incomplete without the sense that one is making a contribution to
others or to a cause. I have to go beyond my own needs and give to others. I
want to give back and to leave a mark on the world.</item>
        <item>By focusing on something beyond myself, most of my problems and
sources of pain become less significant. I get certainty because I know that
there is always a way to contribute. I have variety because there are many
different ways of making a contribution. I have significance because I know
I am helping others. The spiritual bond that develops by helping others
gives me a sense of connection. I grow and develop by helping others.</item>
        <item>I lose sight of the fact that charity begins at home. I care for so many
people or for such an important cause that I sometimes neglect taking care
of my self and my loved ones.</item>
        <item>A consequence is that my physical, emotional or spiritual health may
suffer. I sometimes neglect my personal relationships and people can
become resentful of the time and energy I put into a cause.</item>
        <item>My focus is on the world, a cause, how to help others, how to contribute.</item>
        <item>I\'m energetic and focused outwardly to the point that I can exhaust myself.</item>
        <item>I would like to stay healthy, but my need to contribute may drive me to
neglect myself and my health.</item>
        <item>I avoid being weak, dependent and powerless. I don\'t want to lose the
respect of the people I care about.</item>
        <item>I\'m brave, persistent, generous and assertive.</item>
        <item>I\'m energetic and firm but can be seen as controlling and disregarding of
others\' opinions. Words that I use frequently are: ideals, justice, the cause,
fairness, compassion, and giving.</item>
        <item>I can over exert myself and suffer from fatigue. Injustice stresses me. It\'s
difficult for me to restrain myself from being confrontational in the face of
unfairness or injustice.</item>
        <item>I become defensive with people who try to control me and with people that
are deceitful. I\'m defensive when people are indifferent to important
causes and ideals.</item>
        <item>I\'m enthusiastic and outgoing but I can become angry and confrontational.</item>
        <item>My goal is to find a balance between taking care of myself, my loved ones,
and my need to contribute to the larger good.</item>
        <item>I need to notice that I can come across as too intense. I need to take care of
myself. I need to take care of my relationships.</item>
        <item>Contribution satisfies all my needs at such a high level that I often ignore
my own needs and neglect my self and others. My lifestyle can lead to
exhaustion. My need to always be strong and deny my vulnerability
interferes with my goal.</item>
        <item>Others can encourage me to take care of my self and to express my
vulnerabilities. They can stand their ground in expressing what they need
from me in terms of attention and energy.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="combination_need_header">
        <item>What you should know about this composition</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="certainty_uncertainty_need_value">
        <item>I may sometimes have inner turmoil and conflict since these are conflicting
needs. Sometimes I want to stay put, be comfortable and make sure that I
feel safe and secure. At other times I seek change, variety in my activities,
and suspense. I want to take risks and feel excited. This inner conflict
affects my relationships since people aren\'t sure of what it is that I truly
want, and therefore they don\'t know how to help me to fulfill my needs.
When I have certainty, I crave uncertainty/variety. And when I have
uncertainty/variety, I crave certainty. It often seems to me that I will never
have enough of either one. At work, I need a comfortable, organized,
predictable environment, yet I also need uncertainty, new experiences and
challenges, which might be disconcerting to fellow workers.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="certainty_significance_need_value">
        <item>I may have inner conflict because significance can only be accomplished by
comparing yourself to others, by being competitive, being out there in the
world and by taking risks. On the other hand, I don\'t want to be
competitive, to take risks or to be out there in the world. Because of my
need for certainty I have trouble involving myself with people, yet I can
only satisfy my need for significance by comparing myself to others. I need
the certainty of knowing that I\'m significant and important, and this makes
it difficult to get along with me. It\'s difficult for me to truly love and take
care of others because I am so focused on my inner feelings.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="certainty_love_need_value">
        <item>It\'s important for me to distinguish whether it is certainty or
love/connection that is my number one need. If certainty is number one,
my love will not flow easily, since I need to feel certain before I can freely
give love, and certainty is very difficult to accomplish. If love/connection is
my number one need, my love will flow, even when I don\'t feel certain and
I will be able to love and be loved. Yet, the need for certainty, even when it
is my need number two, will put restraints on my ability to love and to
connect to others. I have trouble at work if I feel that the work environment
is not comfortable, organized, predictable and if I don\'t feel connected and
appreciated by others.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="certainty_growth_need_value">
        <item>My inner conflict is that I want to feel comfortable, safe, and secure. I need
a predictable environment and I don\'t want to take risks. Yet to grow, I
need to put myself out there, take risks, extend the limits of my comfort
and stretch myself. To satisfy my need for certainty, I prefer to avoid new
people and new situations. To satisfy my need for growth I need to become
involved with new people and new situations. This inner conflict
preoccupies me and makes it difficult for people to help me to satisfy my
needs, since they don\'t know whether certainty or growth are more
important to me. One way I can resolve this dilemma is that I can always be
certain that I can grow, because there are always new things to learn and
new skills to be developed. The way to resolve my conflict is to satisfy my
need for certainty by always growing. I might have difficulties at work if I
don\'t feel that I\'m growing and, at the same time, that I am in comfortable,
organized, predictable environment.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="certainty_contribution_need_value">
        <item>If certainty means that I cannot take risks, that everything has to be
predictable and that I must always feel comfortable, then certainty and
contribution are conflicting needs. In order to contribute, I need to put
myself out there, take risks and the results are not always predictable.
However, if I can satisfy my need for certain by contributing, then there is
no inner conflict. I can always be certain that I will contribute. Everyone
can contribute beyond oneself and I can be sure that I will find ways of
making a contribution to others. At work, my need for certainty might
interfere with my need to contribute to the people I work with, if I feel they
are not collaborating sufficiently in creating a predictable, organized work
environment.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="uncertainty_significance_need_value">
        <item>I can sometimes have the inner conflict that I like uncertainty, variety,
suspense, risk and yet I want to always feel important, significant. When
there is uncertainty and things are unpredictable, I cannot be sure that I
will experience the sense of being important and significant that I crave.
Yet if I don\'t face uncertainty, I can\'t be sure that I will feel significant
enough. My need for both uncertainty/variety and significance can
sometimes lead me to be too competitive and confrontational with people,
and therefore it can be difficult to get along with me. One solution to my
inner conflict is for me to experience significance precisely because I\'m
capable of experiencing uncertainty and variety, rather than because I\'m
more important and more competitive than others. I may be a difficult
person to work with because I want to always feel important and my need
for uncertainty/variety interferes with the ability to be organized and
efficient. My need for both significance and uncertainty/variety may lead
me to neglect my health and to risk injuries in sports and other activities.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="uncertainty_love_need_value">
        <item>It can be difficult for me to have a stable, long-term relationship with a
partner or spouse. There are too many tempting possibilities for
uncertainty and variety out there. I might seek to satisfy my need for
uncertainty/variety by getting involved with other people that threaten my
primary relationship or by getting involved with activities that take me
away from my partner. This conflict is exacerbated if the number one need
is uncertainty/variety and love/connection is second, because it will
be difficult for me to love and take care of the people that are important
in my life. If love/connection is the first need and uncertainty/variety is
second, it will not be easy but I will be able to give priority to the ones I
love instead of to my need for new experiences. Work may be difficult for
me if I don\'t feel there are sufficient variety and a good connection with the
people I work with. In terms of health, I might exhaust myself trying to
give enough time to fulfilling both my need for love/connection and for
love.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="uncertainty_growth_need_value">
        <item>These needs are not incompatible or conflicting and I will be able to satisfy
my need for uncertainty/variety through my personal growth, and my need
for growth through new experiences that give me the uncertainty/variety
that I need. However, because these are my two most important needs, I
tend not to focus sufficiently on relationships and on the people I care
about. People might feel that I don\'t give them enough and that I don\'t
truly love them. Work may be difficult for me if I don\'t feel that there is
sufficient variety and opportunity for growth. In terms of health and safety,
I might take too many risks that may result in injuries or health problems.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="uncertainty_contribution_need_value">
        <item>These needs are not incompatible or conflicting and I will be able to satisfy
my need for uncertainty/variety by contributing to others, and I will be
able to satisfy my need for contribution by finding different ways of
contributing. However, because these are my two most important needs, I
tend not to focus sufficiently on relationships and on the people I care
about. People might feel that I don\'t give them enough and that I don\'t
truly love them. Work may be difficult for me if I don\'t feel that there is
sufficient variety and opportunity to contribute. In terms of health and
safety, I might take too many risks that may result in injuries or health
problems.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="significance_love_need_value">
        <item>I will have trouble fulfilling my need for love/connection because it\'s
difficult to love someone who has to feel important all the time. I have a
better chance if love/connection is my first need, but even so I will
experience difficulties. I have a hard time experiencing love/connection
when I don\'t feel important and respected at the same time. I sometimes
try to feel connected and loved because I\'m so important and this is
precisely what pushes people away from me. If I feel insignificant, I feel
unloved and I might attempt to feel connected through confrontation and
intimidation. This makes it difficult to work with me and to be in a longterm
stable relationship.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="significance_growth_need_value">
        <item>My inner conflict is that to grow I have to be willing to accept that there are
new things for me to learn and new skills that I can develop. Yet,
sometimes my need to feel significant makes me think that I already know
everything. This inner conflict is more troubling if significance comes first
and growth comes second. When growth is first, I can satisfy my need for
significance by growing, developing new skills and learning. Because these
are my two most important needs, people might feel that I\'m not
sufficiently connected to them and that I don\'t\' care enough for them. I
might be difficult to work with because I\'m so focused on myself. I tend to
take good care of my health when it\'s part of my need to feel that I\'m
growing and that I\'m important.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="significance_contribution_need_value">
        <item>My inner conflict is that to fulfill my need to contribute, I have to focus on
others, and not on myself; and to fulfill my need for feeling important and
significant, I have to focus on myself and not on others. This inner conflict
can be resolved if I\'m able to satisfy my need for significance through the
contributions I make to others. Because these are my two most important
needs, family members and important people in my life might feel that I\'m
not sufficiently connected to them and that I don\'t care enough about
them. I might be difficult to work with because I\'m so focused on what is
important to me. I might neglect my health if I feel that taking care of
myself physically and emotionally interferes with my need to gain
importance and to make a contribution.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="love_growth_need_value">
        <item>My inner conflict is that my need for personal growth interferes with
putting enough focus and energy on connecting with others and on giving
and receiving love. In order to grow, I have to focus on myself and not on
others; and in order to satisfy my need for love/connection, I have to focus
on others and not on myself. This inner conflict can be resolved if I\'m able
to satisfy my need for growth through love and connection to others. When
growth is my first need, I may not be able to feel loved and connected
unless I feel I\'m growing. When love/connection comes first, I may not be
able to feel that I\'m growing unless I\'m connected and loved. I often want
my spouse or partner to participate in my growth experiences so I can feel
connected and loved through growth.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="love_contribution_need_value">
        <item>If my need for contribution comes first, I have trouble with those I love as
they might feel that contributing to others or to the world is more
important to me than they are. This conflict is less severe if my first need is
for love/connection and contribution is second, since I will only be able to
fulfill my need for contribution if I feel love and connection. This conflict is
resolved if my need to contribute is in great part fulfilled through my need
to give love to others. I often want my spouse or partner to participate in
the contributions I make so I can feel connected and loved through
contribution.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="growth_contribution_need_value">
        <item>I might have trouble with those I love because they may feel that my need
to grow and to contribute is more important to me than they are. They
might feel neglected and resentful. This conflict can be resolved if my need
for growth and contribution includes contributing to those I love and
helping them to grow in the ways that they want to grow. I might have
conflicts with my spouse or partner if I want him/her to value growth and
contribution in the same way I do.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="statements">
        <item>People are impressed by me.</item>
        <item>Feeling that I belong is important to me.</item>
        <item>I need to feel grounded.</item>
        <item>I don\'t mind taking risks.</item>
        <item>I don\'t fear change.</item>
        <item>A failure is not a failure if you keep trying.</item>
        <item>I believe in giving back.</item>
        <item>I\'m good at taking care of people.</item>
        <item>I often worry about what people are saying about me.</item>
        <item>I like to have as much stability in my life as possible.</item>
        <item>It’s important to contribute to your community.</item>
        <item>I like to develop new ideas and projects.</item>
        <item>I\'m security conscious.</item>
        <item>I like to be an example to others.</item>
        <item>I\'m competitive.</item>
        <item>I hate the feeling of boredom.</item>
        <item>I know how to make connections with people.</item>
        <item>I constantly aspire to improve.</item>
        <item>Danger is never exciting to me.</item>
        <item>In most close relationships I\'m usually the giver.</item>
        <item>There is always something new to be learned.</item>
        <item>I need to feel fulfilled.</item>
        <item>I frequently evaluate myself.</item>
        <item>I like for things to be predictable.</item>
        <item>I am more loving than most people.</item>
        <item>Recognition is very important to me.</item>
        <item>I like the feeling of exertion.</item>
        <item>I\'m very careful of not over spending.</item>
        <item>Education is important to me.</item>
        <item>I\'m a leader.</item>
        <item>I\'m always looking for new experiences.</item>
        <item>I sometimes over extend myself trying to help others.</item>
        <item>My routines and habits are important to me.</item>
        <item>I take pride in who I am.</item>
        <item>I like how learning something new changes my perspective.</item>
        <item>Sometimes the most important work is not what you get paid for.</item>
        <item>I\'m not an adventurous person.</item>
        <item>No one would say that I\'m selfish.</item>
        <item>I tend to spend beyond my limits.</item>
        <item>I like to feel important.</item>
        <item>Every failure is a learning experience.</item>
        <item>I like to learn in order to teach what I learn.</item>
        <item>I seek unity in my relationship.</item>
        <item>I like to make a difference.</item>
        <item>If I don\'t know the consequences, I refrain from acting.</item>
        <item>I suffer when I feel blocked.</item>
        <item>I enjoy suspense.</item>
        <item>Prestige is very important to me.</item>
        <item>I\'m a romantic.</item>
        <item>I\'m constantly learning.</item>
        <item>Giving is more important to me than receiving.</item>
        <item>I like to be number one.</item>
        <item>I hate taking risks of any kind.</item>
        <item>I like to constantly develop myself.</item>
        <item>I like to give my energy to good causes.</item>
        <item>I like to be admired by others.</item>
        <item>I\'m proud of my ability to learn new things.</item>
        <item>We are here to make this world a better place.</item>
        <item>I like to grow and develop in different areas.</item>
        <item>Personal relationships are the most important thing in my life.</item>
        <item>Sometimes I can be intimidating.</item>
        <item>I often look for new forms of entertainment.</item>
        <item>I\'m concerned about anything that might be risky.</item>
        <item>Being fulfilled by work is more important than being admired.</item>
        <item>I strive to improve my skills.</item>
        <item>I get close to people by being generous with time, money &amp; energy.</item>
        <item>I like to think carefully before I go into action.</item>
        <item>Sometimes I like the thrill of experiencing fear.</item>
        <item>I need to feel respected.</item>
        <item>When we stop growing, we die.</item>
        <item>The feeling of togetherness is important to me.</item>
        <item>For life to make sense, you have to leave a mark in the world.</item>
        <item>Feeling comfortable at all times is important to me.</item>
        <item>I enjoy being involved in many different activities.</item>
        <item>I\'m always comparing myself to others in terms of success.</item>
        <item>I need to have passion in my relationship.</item>
        <item>If I\'m not contributing to others, my life is meaningless.</item>
        <item>When making a decision, I think about what is most enjoyable.</item>
        <item>I can\'t stand to feel stagnant.</item>
        <item>I need to feel as safe as possible at all times.</item>
        <item>If I commit, I worry that I\'ll miss out on something better.</item>
        <item>I never want to be seen as a loser.</item>
        <item>I don\'t care about having much stability in my life.</item>
        <item>I have a mission.</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>
